

LinkedIn(Link)

Email: mithun.das227@gmail.com Mobile: +8801833994177

SUMMARY

Passionate software engineer with 5+ years of experience involved in the development of successfully delivered B2B applications implementing the standard software development procedure and cutting-edge technologies. My biggest strength is my perseverance, my enthusiasm to learn new things and doing adequate research where necessary.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: C, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript

Backend Framework: .NET CoreFrontend Framework: Angular

• Database: SQL, NoSQL(MongoDB), Redis

• Unit Testing Framework: NUnit

• Message Broker: Kafka

• Collaboration Tools: Git, JIRA, Hubstaff

Work Experience

WebCreek

The Woodlands, USA

July 2022 - Present

- Sofyware Engineer(Remote Job)
 - Developed products for a US-based industrial equipment dealership company where digital solutions were provided for their entire operations.
 - o Developed products using EntityFramework, MSSQL database, and Angular.
 - Used ASP.NET Zero framework for multi-tenant support.
 - Performed Unit Testing using NUnit Framework.
 - Worked in a diverse work culture where our team members were from 15+ different countries.

SELISE Digital Platforms

Zurich, Switzerland Oct 2017 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer(Dhaka office)

- Developed the digital product for the renowned European insurance company Swiss Life where the product was used across more than 45 countries.
- Automated some complex calculations systems like pooling simulation which used to take a huge time before our solution.
- Worked as a team lead for some particular features and designed databases(MongoDB) for large systems.
- Worked on microservice based architecture and implemented CQRS design pattern with event sourcing and Kafka.
- Closely involved with the client for requirement analysis.
- Used Angular, .net core, and RabbitMQ for backend infrastructure.
- Used agile methodology and JIRA for the development process.

EDUCATION

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology, Sylhet

Jan 2013 - Jan 2020

B.Sc. (Engineering) in Computer Science and Engineering; GPA: 3.11 out of 4.00;

Govt. City College, Chittagong

Oct 2010 - Aug 2012

Higher Secondary School Certificate(Science Group); Grade: 5.00 out of 5.00

Saint Placid's High School, Chittagong

Jan 2006 - Mar 2010

Secondary School Certificate (Science Group): Grade: 5.00 out of 5.00

Undergraduate Thesis

• Sachetan "A crowdsource based safety application": making a system which will show a safe path from the current location to the destination on Google map and shows the statistical and analytical reports of dangerous accidents such as mugging, robbery, theft, sexual harassment take place for a specific area. (Published in Springer 2019 conference India)

PROGRAMMING AND PROBLEM SOLVING ACTIVITIES

- 367 UVA Problems solved (username: mithun_SUST).
- Regular codeforce contestant during 2014-2015 (username: Mithun_SUST)
- 70+ problems solved at LightOj (username: Mithun Das)
- 100+ problems solved at Hackerrank (username: mithun_sust)
- Regular programming contestant at University during 2013-2015

EXTRA CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Data Science Enthusiast (Kaggle certification links are attached below):
 - Python Course Certification (Link)
 - Introductory Machine Learning (Link)
 - Intermediate Machine Learning (Link)
- Udemy Course Certifications
 - Unit Testing For C# Developers (Link)
 - .NET Microservices: CQRS and Event Sourcing with Kafka (Link)
 - Build an app with ASPNET Core and Angular from scratch (Link)
- Story writer in Medium (Link)